Жахлива заява Отані!
Otani's Catastrophic Declaration!!
Нобу отримала запрошення на навчання з університету Хоккайдо,
Nobu-chan received her acceptance notice from the undergraduate university in Hokkaido,
і стала приязнішою з Накао.
and she's been even more lovey-dovey with Nakao-chi than before.
Отані, прагнучи стати вчителем,
Otani, who wants to become a teacher, has started attending prep classes,
ретельно готується до вступних іспитів.
and is studying seriously for the entrance exams.
Я не люблю навчання та тести,
I don't like studying or taking tests,
тож обрала технікум замість універу.
so I've given up on the idea of going to university and decided to try for a technical college instead.
Гей, Отані...
Hey, Otani...
Що?
What?
Підемо на концерт Умібозу?
What do you want to do about the next Umibouzu Concert?
Я пас.
I'm gonna pass this time.
Це ж Умібозу!
This is Umibouzu we're talking about!
Це останній концерт року!
It's the last Umibouzu concert of the year!
Я знаю. Але вибору немає.
I know! But I don't really have a choice.
Маю готуватись до іспитів.
This is the only time I have to study for exams.
Ледь не ридав, коли рішив не йти.
I was choking back tears when I finally decided not to go.
То он як...
I see...
Дурепо! А хто обіцявся підтримувати мене?!
Idiot! Who was it who said she was going to support me?!
Абітурієнтам мабуть важко.
Examinees sure have it hard.
Передразнюєш мене?
Are you mocking me?
Та ні.
Not really.
Якщо ні, то годі базікати, поки я намагаюсь запам'ятати англійські слова, трясця.
If not, stop talking to me while I'm trying to memorize English vocab. Geez.
Зажди, Отані.
Wait, Otani.
Замовкни. Чого прилипла?
Be quiet. Why are you following me anyway?
З чого це ти взяв, я маю свої справи.
No need to put it like that. I've got a reason for coming this way.
Га? Справи?
Huh? A reason?
Підробіток.
My part-time job.
У кафе навпроти твоєї школи.
It's at the restaurant opposite your prep school.
Чого це ти раптом влаштувалась?
Why are you working all of a sudden?
Так я хоча б можу провести тебе.
This way I can at least walk you halfway home.
Метелик сидить криво.
Your ribbon isn't on straight.
Вибачте.
Sorry.
Нігті задовгі, обріж їх, будь ласка.
And your nails are too long. Please cut them before you come tomorrow.
Волосся затягни сильніше.
And tie your hair up tighter.
Добре!
S-Sure!
Сувора.
How strict.
Кохорі!
Kohori-kun!
Що?
That gave me a start!
Ти спізнився.
You're five minutes late.
Пробачте.
I-I'm sorry.
Другий день поспіль.
And this is the second day in a row.
Мене затримав учитель.
I was held back at school by my teacher.
Я вже попереджала, щоб у таких випадках ти дзвонив.
I already told you to call ahead if that happens.
Ще сумісник? Який милий.
Another part-timer? What a cute boy.
Напульсник з Умібозу!
An Umibouzu wristband!
З обмеженої концертної колекції!
And it's the limited edition one that you can only get at his concerts!
Га?
Huh?
Ти теж фанатка?
Don't tell me you're a huge Umibouzu fan too?
Мега фанатка!
A mega fan!
І я!
Same here!
Як круто мати іншого фаната поруч!
It's awesome to have another Umibouzu fan around!
Ура! Я такий щасливий!
Yay! I'm feeling all excited now!
Коїзумі! Кохорі! Припиніть це негайно!
Koizumi-san! Kohori-kun! Stop that right now!
Пробачте...
Sorry...
Які смачнющі данґо!
These dumplings are just delicious!
Справді.
They really are.
Подобаються?
You like them?
Звісно. Це ж ти їх зробив.
Of course. You made them, after all.
Отже, який він, твій колега по кухні?
So what's this younger kitchen-hand co-worker of yours like?
Ти про Кохорі?
Oh, Konori-kun?
Миле личко і на зріст як Отані.
His face is kind of cute, and he's about as tall as Otani...
Фетиш на коротунів говорить?
Is your midget fetish speaking to you?
Який ще фетиш?!
Who's got a midget fetish?!
Схоже, що Отані наполегливо працює.
Come to think of it, Otani-kun seems to be working really hard.
Га?
Really?
Та ну. Отані?
No way. Otani-kun is?
Чула він засидівся допізна, розпитуючи вчителя.
I heard he stayed back late yesterday, and was asking the teacher lots of questions.
Он як...
is that so...
Отані справді старається.
Otani really is trying.
Огоооо..
Oooooh...
Все вірно.
That's correct.
Гааа?
Huh?
Неможливо!
N-No way!
Як і казав, якщо постараюсь, то все зможу.
Like I said: if I put my mind to it, I can do it.
Правда?
Seriously?
В такому разі вступ для нього цілком можливий.
At this rate, getting into college won't be impossible for him.
Щодо мене...
In comparison, I...
треба вирішити своє майбутнє.
I need to decide what I'm going to do with myself.
Може влаштуватись на повний день.
Maybe I should just start doing this full time...
Коїзумі!
Koizumi-san!
Вибачте.
I'm sorry.
Виба-
Sorr-
Аййй!
Owww!
Коїзумі!
Koizumi-san!
Трясця, яка я нездара.
Man... I really can't do anything.
Не варто зчиняти такий ґвалт.
You shouldn't always make so much of a fuss.
А я ще й на повну ставку зібралась.
And I was thinking of doing this full time?
Пробачте.
I'm sorry.
Раночку!
Good morning!
Думаю, тут бракує солі.
I think it needs more salt.
Було ж засолодко.
It was too sweet, was it?
Я не зрозуміла.
I don t get this part.
Погляньмо...
Let's see...
Ця формула...
Use this formula...
Що з вами?!
Wh-What's up with all of you?!
Ніби збираєтесь у майбутнє!
It's like you're all ready to fly off into the future!
О, Рісо, ти тут? Раночку.
Oh, Risa, you're here? Good morning.
Спробую додати ямсу до рецепту.
Maybe I should add yams to the recipe.
Милий, ти геній!
Darling, you're a genius!
Ти станеш чудовим шефом.
You'll definitely become a great artisan.
Що коїться?
Wh-What's going on?
Чомусь... чомусь...
Somehow... somehow...
почуваю себе облишеною.
I feel like I'm being left behind.
Ну і пика.
My face looks terrible.
Знову насварять.
I'll get yelled at again.
Посмішка, посмішка.
Smile, smile.
Ласкаво прошу!
Welcome!
Ви чули її?
She said "Welcome."
Чого приперлися?
What did you come here for?
Отак ти поводишся з клієнтами? Як грубо.
You're saying, "What did you come here for" to your customers? How rude.
Вкалуєш?
Working hard?
Чого вам? Прийшли посміятися?
What is this? Did you come just to laugh at me?
Пробачте. Поведінка цієї офіціантки жахливе.
Excuse me. This waitress's attitude is terrible.
Що замовлятимете?
Please let me know what you would like to order.
Як дивно!
How weird!
Сміхота!
How funny!
Дайте закінчити.
At least let me finish.
Прошу...
P-P-P-P-P-P-Please go ahead...
Боляче, дурепо, я взагалі-то клієнт.
Hey, that hurt, you idiot! I'm a customer, you know.
А як же підготовчі?
What happened to studying?
Все ок.
I am.
Скоро піду туди.
I'm going to prep class in a bit.
Га?
Huh?
Навіть у неділю?
They even hold them on Sundays?
Для вступаючих немає вихідних.
There are no weekends for examinees.
Особливо для двієчників.
Especially not for the ones with bad grades.
Та, та-
Exactly, exact-
Годі, годі.
Hey. Enough, enough.
Рісо, а де той милий колега, про якого ти згадувала? Він не на зміні?
Say Risa, where's that cute kitchen-hand you mentioned last time? Not working today?
Кохорі? Схоже його немає сьогодні.
Oh, Kohori-kun? Doesn't look like he's here today.
Що за хлопець?
Who is this guy?
Наступна ціль фетишистки Ріси.
Midget fetishist Risa's next target.
Фетишистки?
Midget fetishist?
Я ж казала, це не так!
I told you it's not like that!
Що? Він коротун?
What? So that guy is short too?
Ні! Це неважливо.
No! That s not important!
Він фанат Умібозу.
He's a huge Umibouzu fan.
Та ну! Правда?
No way! Seriously?
На мене кричатимуть за базікання.
I'll get yelled at if I keep talking.
Моє замовлення...
Uh, my order...
Що ж... Схоже вона щасливіща, ніж я очікував.
Well, well... She seems a lot happier than I expected.
Справді?
Oh really?
Казав, що прийдеш посміятися, але насправді хвилювався, так?
You said you came to laugh at her, but you were actually worried about her, weren't you?
Бо їй було погано через зауваження на роботі.
Since she was down about continually getting chewed out before.
Що?
What?
Так?
Right?
Так, так.
Right, right.
Як мило!
How cute!
Це не так, дурні!
It's not like that, you idiots!
У вступників немає часу хвилюватися за інших.
An examinee's got no time to worry about others.
Ти знову?
That again?
Диви, Ріса так підчепить цього хлопця.
If you're like that, Risa will hook up with that cute short kid behind your back.
Так, так, так!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Не дуркуйте.
Don t be stupid.
Он як. Тож Отані має заняття і в неділю?
I see. So Otani has class on Sundays too?
Дякую за підтримку.
Thank you for your patronage.
Старайся.
Work hard.
Бувай, Рісо.
See ya, Risa.
А я хотіла з ним погуляти наступної неділі.
I was planning to go out with him next Sunday since I'll have the day off.
Він вступник, що ж поробиш.
Oh well. He's an examinee; it can't be helped.
Морок
Gloom
Що за дивний гнітючий настрій?
What's with this odd, gloomy atmosphere?
У чому справа?
What's the matter?
Стулися, дурепо. Не мов до мене.
Shut up, idiot. Don't talk to me.
Рісо, сюди, сюди.
Risa, over here, over here.
Чули він погано склав пробні.
We heard he did terribly in the practice exams.
По всім потрібним предметам - трійки.
The results for his top choice school were all C's.
Це погано?
Is that bad?
Дуже.
It's very bad.
Якого біса?!
What the hell?!
Я навіть сном пожертвував...
I even sacrificed sleep for study...
Чому...
Why...
Що ж, навіть якщо починаєш готуватися, то оцінки не підскочать одразу.
Well, even if you start studying now, you can't expect your grades to go up right away.
Ще є час, не переймайся.
You've still got time, so don't worry.
Легко сказати.
That's easy for you to say.
Я хвилююсь за тебе.
I'm worried about you.
Ти так себе змучиш.
You'll wear yourself out at this rate.
Заціпся! Облиш мене!
Shut up! Just leave me alone!
Що... Ти здурів!
What the... You're just crazy!
Так не поможеш!
This has nothing to do with anything like that!
Патякаєш що заманеться!
Stop blurting out whatever comes into your head!
Добре. Як знаєш.
Fine. Do what you like.
Справлюся й сам.
I would've done that without you telling me.
Та що це?!
What the heck?!
Що коїться?
Я йому заважаю?
What was that all about?
Am I getting in his way?
Я розумію його напругу, але хіба він не був приємнішим?
I know he's under a lot of stress, but couldn't he have been a little nicer?
Коїзумі!
Koizumi- san!
Кохорі.
Oh, Kohori-kun.
Ура, ми знову разом!
Yay! We're on together again today!
Що це?! Що трапилось?!
What's with that?! What happened?!
А. Порізався, поки гострив ножа.
Oh. I cut myself just now when I was sharpening the knives.
Думав що робити...
I was wondering what to do about it...
Ось.
There.
Красно дякую.
Thanks so much.
Я постійно б'ю стакани й ріжуся, тож постійно тягаю аптечку.
I break glasses and cut my hands all the time, so I've had to use the first aid kit a lot.
Стара пані Мацумара допомогла мені першого разу,
Old lady Matsumara helped me at first.
але далі сказала розбиратись самі.
but I kept getting hurt, so she told me I should deal with it myself.
Вона розізлиться на "стару".
She'll get angry if she hears you calling her an old lady.
Чорт! Вона ж не поруч?
Crap! She's not here, is she?
Ти дотепна, Коїузмі.
You're pretty funny, Koizumi-san.
Дотепна і добра. Ти чудова людина.
You're really funny and kind. You re a great person.
А, ні, ні...
Ah, no, no...
Правда.
Seriously.
Я працюю тут шість місяців, але вперше зустрічаю таку як тебе.
I've been working here for six months, but this is the first time I've met someone like you.
Га?
Huh?
Тебе навіть на кухні знають.
Even in the kitchen, you're famous.
Чуємо твоє волання з зали.
We can always hear you shouting from outside.
"Ойййййй!" або "Пробачте!"
Like "Whoops!" or" I'm so sorry!"
О ні!
Oh no!
Стара Мацумара свариться, що я така галаслива.
I get yelled at by old lady Matsumara for shouting loudly like that too...
Стоп. Я знову сказала "стара".
Wait. I called her "old lady" again.
Трясця! Її точно немає десь поруч?
Man! She's definitely not around, right? Right?
Так смішно! Зараз лусну!
You re so funny! My stomach hurts from laughing!
Що ж, мені ліпше.
Well, I'm feeling better now, at any rate.
Прогноз погоди не помилився. Добре, що я взяв парасолю.
The weather forecast was correct. I was right to bring my umbrella.
У тебе є час, не хвилюйся.
You've still got time, so don't worry.
Так я хоча б можу провести тебе.
This way I can at least walk you halfway home.
Вона скоріше за все без парасолі.
She... probably didn't bring an umbrella.
Пані Мацумаро, чи всі страви з меню є на виніс?
Matsumara- san, is everything on our menu is available for take-out?
Так.
Yes.
І якщо не вивчиш сьогодні меню, я тебе не відпущу додому.
And if you don't memorize the entire menu tonight, I'm not letting you go home.
Тут так багато літер. Мене хилить в сон вже від їх виду.
Well, there sure is a lot of text. I'm getting sleepy just looking at it.
Ти помиляєшся, бо не знаєш меню!
You make mistakes because you don't know the menu!
Я пам'ятаю усі рамени!
I've memorized all of the noodle meals perfectly!
Звісно що. У нас їх аж два.
Of course you have. We only have two.
Що ж. Все це можна замовити на виніс.
Right. So all of these menu items can also be take-out...
Може узяти щось для Отані на вечерю...
Maybe I should get something for Otani to have for dinner.
Я пішов.
I'm leaving now.
Добре. Гарна робота.
Right. Good work.
Що поробиш. Що поробиш.
Can't be helped~ Can't be helped~
Що поробиш.
Can't be helped~
Га?
Huh?
Коїзумі? Чому ти спиш тут?
Koizumi-san? Why are you sleeping here?
Коїзумі?
Koizumi-san?
Агов!
Hey!
Якщо принесу йому вечерю, Отані здивується.
If I bring him dinner, Otani will probably be surprised.
Га?
Huh?
Що?
What...?
Це було,
That was, uhhh... S-S-S-
Це було... Вибач!
That was, uhhh... S-S-S-S-S-Sorry!
Я н-н-не...ц-ц-цей... еммм... цей... Я не цілував тебе...
I w-wasn't... th-that... uh... th-this... I wasn't kissing you...
Отані! Зажди!
Otani! Wait!
Усе не так, Отані. Послухай!
It's not what you think, Otani. Please listen!
То ось про що казала Нобу?
So that was who Nobu-chan was talking about?
Фетишистка!
Midget fetishist!
Це не так!
It's not like that!
Ем, Отані...
Um, Otani...
Я вчуся. Прошу, тихіше.
I'm studying. Please be quiet.
Ранку.
Morning.
Що таке?
What's going on?
Вона зрадила мені з коротуном.
She cheated on me with that midget she works with.
Що?!
What?!
Ти помиляєшся!
I told you, you got it all wrong!
Як я можу?!
How am I wrong?!
Я чітко бачив. Він точно тебе цілував.
I saw it clearly. He definitely kissed you.
Це...
That...
Це було...
That was...
Не уявляю...
I had no idea...
Тебе в мені цікавить лише тіло?
So you only wanted me for my body?
Га?
Huh?
То неважливо який він? Ти збоченка!
So it doesn't matter who it is, as long as they're short? You pervert!
Якого біса!
Like hell!
Хто б навмисне шукав нижчого хлопця? Це ж відстій!
Who would deliberately look for a boyfriend shorter than them? Thats so uncool!
Відстій? Це виходить і я відстій?!
Uncool? You're calling me uncool?!
Не можу повірити.
I don't believe it.
Не дивлячись як Отані зайнятий...
No matter how busy Otani is with his exams...
Не думала, що ти зрадиш.
I never thought you would two-time him!
Ні...
No...
Я думала ти не така, Рісо!
I didn't think you were like that, Risa!
Я розчарований.
I'm so disappointed.
Збоченка!
Pervert!
Вислухайте мене!
Will you just listen to me?!
Ти заснула?
You fell asleep?
Кажу ж, нічого не відбувається.
I'm telling you, there's absolutely nothing going on.
Можеш так казати, але він зробив таке.
You might say there isn't, but he went and did something like that...
Хто знає, що він думає?
Who knows what he thinks?
Навіть якщо ти запитаєш, я не знаю.
I don't know, even if you ask me.
Він щось сказав?
Did he say anything?
Ні.
Not really.
То спитай!
So ask!
Але ми вже закінчили роботу... і якби я лишилася побалакати, на мене б накричали.
But we'd already finished work... and if I'd stayed to chat, I would've been yelled at.
Дурепа.
Idiot.
Зажди. Чесно, я тобі не зраджую.
Wait. Honestly, I'm not two-timing you.
Я можу тобі довіряти?
Can I believe you?
Звісно.
Of course.
Тоді передай коротуну.
Then tell that shorty.
Що?
Tell him what?
Наступного разу
Next time he tries to lay a hand on you,
я зламаю йому носа.
I'll give him a hook so hard his nose will be crooked.
Може не варто..
Maybe you shouldn't punch him in the nose...
Я серйозно. Так і зроблю.
I'm serious. I'll really do it.
Треба було ще тоді вмазати.
I should've hit him when I had the chance.
Те, що він засмучений цим - радує мене.
Seeing him this upset over me makes me kind of happy.
Це не привід для сміху, дурепо.
This is no laughing matter, idiot.
Вибач за вчорашнє! Це був момент слабкості і я зрозумів.
I'm sorry about yesterday! It was a moment of weakness, and by the time I realized...
А...
Ah...
То був твій хлопець? Дуже вибачаюсь!
That was your boyfriend, right? I'm so sorry!
Кохорі...
Kohori-kun...
Це пусте. Справді.
It's no big deal. Really.
Не злишся?
You're not mad?
Та ні. Я спала, тож нічого не пам'ятаю.
Not really. I was asleep anyway, so I don't remember a thing.
Слава богу.
Thank goodness.
А... тож...
Um... well...
Що таке?
What is it?
Зайнята у неділю?
Are you busy this Sunday?
Га?
Huh?
Буде захід з Умібозу.
There's an Umibouzu event.
Умібозу... Умібозу... Умібозу...
Umibouzu... Umibouzu... Umibouzu...
Справді? Що за захід?
Really? What kind of event?
Це для радіо. Лише 50 місць.
It's a radio event. Only fifty people get to go.
Вау! І ти виграв?
Wow! And you won?
Так! Запрошую тебе. Добре?
Yes! And I'd like to invite you. Is that okay?
Навіть якщо один раз.
Even if it's just this once...
Хочу піти з тобою, Коїзумі.
I'd really like to go with you, Koizumi-san.
Я не турбуватиму тебе!
I won't do anything that will make trouble for you!
Не хочеш?
You don't want to come?
Ем...
Um...
Що мені робити?
Wh-What should I do?
Чи можу я піти? Враховуючи усе, то не варто б.
Can I go? Taking everything into consideration, it's obvious that I shouldn't...
Навіть якщо він мені нецікавий, піти з ним на концерт після того, що трапилося...
Even if I'm not interested in him, going to a concert with him after what happened is...
Цього разу не буде виправдань.
There's no excuse this time.
Не можу.
I can't.
Ні за що. Ні за що.
No way. No way.
Ні! Ні! Ні! Ні!
No way! No way! No way! No way!
То виходить, що ні?
So... it s a "no," then?
О Боже!
Oh my God!
Я йду.
I'll come.
Ура!!!
Yay!!!
Ура, ура, ура!
Yay, yay, yay!
Я жахлива дурепа!
Не можу йому відмовити!
I'm the world's biggest idiot!
I couldn't say no to him!
Це не зрада.
Ми просто йдемо на концерт.
But it's not cheating.
We're just going to a concert.
Швиденько туди й назад додому.
I'll hurry there and then hurry on home once it's finished.
Агов.
Hey.
Дякую мала!
Thank you baby!
Побачимось наступного року!
See you again at Osaka Castle Hall next year!
Бувай!
Bye bye!
Добре. Завершуємо передачу з концерту Умібозу.
Okay. That ends our broadcast of the Umibouzu concert.
Вона точно зрадіє цьому.
She was at work so she'll definitely be happy when I give this to her.
Це ж був концерт лише по запрошенням!
It was an invite-only concert, after all - a once in a lifetime thing!
Було круто!
That was great!
Я уперше була на такому шоу.
That was my first time seeing Umibouzu perform before such a small audience.
І я, і я!
Me too, me too!
Дякую, що запросив мене.
Thank you for inviting me to such a great event.
Я радий, що покликав тебе. Я щасливий!
I'm glad I finally invited you out. I'm so happy!
Чому?
Why is that?
Коїзумі!
Koizumi-san!
Що?
What?
Взагалі... Я.. перед тобою...
Actually... I... towards you...
Зявилося!!!
It appeared!!!
Що ти робиш?
What are you doing?
Ем...
Um...
Отані...
Otani...
Не смійся! Я задав тобі питання!
Don't laugh! I'm asking you what you're doing!
Все не так!
It's not what you think!
Це я покликав її на концерт Умібозу.
I was the one who pressured her into going to the Umibouzu concert with me.
Коїзумі нічого не зробила поганого!
Koizumi-san didn't do anything wrong!
Кохорі..
Kohori-kun...
Ооо...
Oh...
То ви були удвох на концерті?
So the two of you went to a concert together?
Я просто хотіла на концерт.
It's not like that. I was the one who really wanted to go to the concert.
Це через мене, тому якщо хочеш - ламай мій ніс.
I'm the one who's in the wrong, so if you really want to break someone's nose, break mine.
Отані...
Otani...
Мені все рівно.
Whatever. I don't care anymore.
Як тупо...
How stupid...
Я йду від тебе.
I'm breaking up with you.
Я більше не можу зустрічатись з тобою!
I can't go out with someone like you anymore!
Отані...
Otani...
Не кажи що йдеш.
Don't say you're going to break up with me.
Йди до карлика, Коїзумі.
Do what you want with that midget, Koizumi.
Карлика? Він вище за тебе.
What do you mean, "midget"? He's taller than you.
Стулися!
Shut your mouth!
Зворушливий комплекс. Звор ком.
Lovely Complex~ LoveCom.
Далі: Роздоріжжя у майбутнє
Життєві обставини.
Next: Many Future Paths!!
The Circumstances We All Bear
Роздоріжжя у майбутнє
Життєві обставини.
Many Future Paths!!
The Circumstances We All Bear
Не пропустіть!
Be sure to watch!